More than half the world's population are city dwellers, and, by 2050, the United Nations predicts that seven in ten people will be.
世界上一半以上的人口是城市居民，而联合国预测，到2050年，十分之七的人将是城市居民。
With that in mind, architects are having to consider how architecture influences our emotional wellbeing in urban settings.
考虑到这一点，建筑师们不得不思考建筑如何影响我们在城市环境中的情感福祉。
According to Colin Ellard, a research psychologist at Waterloo University, Canada, there is a lot of evidence which shows "the profound impact that the design of buildings has on how we feel, how we treat one another, and our overall psychological well-being".
加拿大滑铁卢大学的研究心理学家科林·埃拉德表示，有大量证据表明"建筑设计对我们感受、我们如何对待彼此以及我们的整体心理福祉有着巨大的影响"。
A study from the University of Heidelberg concluded that people raised in the countryside are less likely to have mental disorders than those raised in the city.
海德堡大学的一项研究得出结论，在农村长大的人比在城市长大的人更不容易患上精神障碍。
The city of Vancouver in Canada, which is surrounded by mountains and ocean, recognises this need to connect with nature.
被山脉和海洋环绕的加拿大温哥华市认识到了这种与自然联系的需求。
It has included protecting ocean and mountain views in its urban planning guidelines.
该市已将保护海洋和山景纳入其城市规划指导方针。
For example, tall buildings are erected in strategic locations that don't block scenic views for downtown residents.
例如，高楼被建造在特定地点，以免遮挡市中心居民风景优美的景观。
The British designer Thomas Heatherwick wants to make architecture less soulless and boring.
英国设计师托马斯·赫斯维克希望让建筑不那么没有灵魂和枯燥。
He told the Guardian newspaper, "We need to fearlessly demand interestingness… and make buildings that nourish our senses."
他告诉《卫报》："我们需要勇敢地追求趣味性……并建造能够滋养我们感官的建筑。"
He has written a new book, Humanise, where he lists seven characteristics of a boring building.
他写了一本新书《人性化》，在其中列出了乏味的建筑的七个特征。
These include being too flat and straight.
其中包括过于平坦和笔直。
He says lack of depth means light and shadow cannot play on surfaces, while straight lines are at odds with nature and make buildings monotonous.
他说，缺乏深度意味着光和影无法在表面相互作用，而直线与自然不一致，使建筑变得单调。
However, making buildings interesting is not always easy, as architect Rafael Vinoly found out in 2013 when he created the 37-storey skyscraper known as the Walkie Talkie in London.
然而，让建筑变得有趣并不总是那么容易，建筑师拉斐尔·维诺利在2013年建造伦敦37层高的摩天大楼"对讲机"时就发现了这一点。
The building was admired for its curved exterior walls covered in reflective glass.
这座建筑因其覆盖着反光玻璃的弯曲的外部墙壁而受到赞赏。
However, it acted like a magnifying glass and reflected light which melted nearby cars and almost set fire to a carpet.
然而，它像放大镜一样，反射光线，熔化了附近的汽车，并差点点燃了一块地毯。
A screen had to be added to prevent the building causing further damage.
后来不得不添加一个屏障以防止该建筑造成进一步的损害。
So, for your own wellbeing, surround yourself with buildings that bring you joy, and ideally a view of nature.
所以，为了你自己的福祉，让自己被能带来快乐的建筑环绕，并且理想情况下能看到自然风景。